

# Alan McClenaghan

## Summary

A 3x Salesforce and Copado professional with experience of Digital Print and Web Design using HTML, CSS & JavaScript. Alan first encountered Salesforce while working as a Junior Software Tester where he worked alongside Developers to debug web app functionalities. He then joined Revolent Group as a Salesforce Developer, learning both Admin and Developer skills. He gained hands-on experience on the Revols for Good programme, helping develop a Salesforce for Non-Profits project environment. Alan is currently working with Atamis, providing Salesforce procurement software for the public and private sectors, and collaborating with clients to design and deliver bespoke customisations.











## Key skills and attributes

- Org and User Setup
- Security and Access
- Data Modelling and Management
- Sales and Marketing Apps
- Service and Support Apps
- Reports and Dashboards

- User Interface
- **Business Logic and Automation**
- Flows and LWC
- Apex, SOQL, SOSL and DML
- Testing and Debugging
- Environments and Deployment
  Bootstrap
- Adobe Creative Suite (10+ years)
- HTML (6 years)
- CSS (6 years)
- JavaScript and React

## **Education and qualifications**

Salesforce Platform Developer | Certified London / 2020

Salesforce Platform App Builder Certified London / 2020

Salesforce Administrator Certified London / 2020

Copado Administrator Certified London / 2020

Copado Developer Certified London / 2020

React Developer (Nanodegree) Udacity / 2019

Front End Web Development (Techdegree) Treehouse / 2018

NVQ Level 4 in Newspaper Journalism Belfast Institute / 2005 – 2006

MA English (Creative Writing) Queen's University of Belfast / 2000 – 2002

BA English Queen's University of Belfast / 1997 – 2000



## **Experience**

## Salesforce Developer | Revolent Group

#### February 2020 – Present

- Creating Salesforce Developer Orgs to increase Salesforce capabilities with the likes of Flow Builder and Lightning Web Components.
- Reports and Dashboards.
- Security and Access.
- Workflow and Process Automation.
- Data Modelling Objects.
- Development environments.
- Salesforce & Copado certified.

#### Salesforce Consultant | Atamis

June 2021 – Present

- Working with and customising Salesforce procurement software for government agencies.
- Communicating with clients to understand requirements and scope.
- Designing and implementing customisations to client specifications.
- Creating and customising Salesforce objects and fields, page layouts and Lightning Layouts
- Creating Flows, approval processes and other automations to deliver client requirements.
- Maintaining sandboxes and using change sets to deploy changes to Production environments.

### Salesforce Developer | Client Pro Bono Project – Migrant Leaders

September 2020 - March 2021

- o Communicating with clients to understand project requirements and scope.
- Creating documentation to help plan and track the project.
- Designing and implementing project data model.
- Working with and customising Salesforce Non-profit Success Pack.
- Creating and customising Salesforce objects and fields.

## Junior Software Tester | Wunderman Thompson Commerce

August 2019 - December 2019

- Testing Salesforce and Shopify components of commerce websites to ensure they worked as intended and integrated correctly with other systems.
- Worked alongside Salesforce and Shopify Developers.
- Provided bug reports & diagnostics to Developers for any corrections to be made.



### Designer | Kadium Publishing

#### January 2011 - February 2019

- Worked on serval high-profile technology magazines including Networking+, 3 international Wireless Communications and several Yearbooks.
- Designed HTML newsletters and digital edition emails.
- Redesigned and updated company website using modern responsive web techniques.
- Planned, designed and copy-subbed the magazines using InDesign software on Mac.
- Worked with internal colleagues and external clients to design ads and other graphics for both print and web, using InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator software.
- Produced PDFs using Adobe Acrobat and coordinated final magazine publication with printers.

#### Page Editor and Sub Editor | Freelance Designer

May 2009 - January 2011

- Sub-edited and designed magazine pages for Centaur, Incisive Media, IPC and Reed Business Information.
- Copy-edited petrochemical market information for Independent Commodity Intelligence Services.

### Page Editor | Racing Post

July 2008 - May 2009

- Designed and sub-edited pages for daily racing newspaper and weekly sister titles, to strict deadlines, using QuarkXPress and QuarkCopyDesk software on Mac.
- Edited and uploaded material to the internet using inhouse Content Management System.
- Worked as part of a large team of designers, sub-editors and other journalists.

### Sub Editor | Newsquest Media Group Ltd

October 2006 – July 2008

- Designed and sub-edited pages for more than 12 newspaper titles, each with its own deadline, using QuarkXPress and Scribe software on Windows.
- Edited and uploaded material to the internet using inhouse Content Management System.
- Worked as part of a large team of designers, sub-editors and other journalists.
- Named Sub-Editor of the Year at the Newsquest South London Awards 2007 for designing pages "head and shoulders above the rest".